ERIC CHARLES SMITH

UX Designer, UI Engineer

☐ eric@erchsm.me ☐ 508.733.4510 ericsmithux.com ☐ Oakland, CA



Hello, I'm Eric. I love being creative, exploring, broadening my horizons and crafting delightful user experiences in my products. I'm a photography enthusiast and love being outdoors.

EXPERIENCE

March 2015 - May 2015

Perforce - UX Designer

Applied Lean UX principles within a centralized design team via 1-week design sprints. Received & delivered rapid feedback through regular critique sessions. Utilized tools including Sketch, Adobe CC & Proto.io.

Alameda, CA

March 2015 - May 2015

General Assembly - UXDi

Covered best practices for User Experience Design during a 10-week immersive program. Created 5 projects in design teams by applying user-centered design principles.

San Francisco, CA

Sept. 2014 - May 2015

Cisco – UI Engineer

Member of a small team focused on creating a web application that utilized HTML, CSS and Javascript to allow our users to visualize their WAN or Wide Area Network.

San Jose, CA

May 2014 - Sept. 2014

Cisco – Java API Engineer

Member of mid-sized agile team working on the creation of WAN Orchestration Web API's. Worked with JAX-RS to create REST-ful services. Also contributed to the product's developer site.

San Jose, CA

January 2012 - May 2014

People's Market – Co-Manager/Owner

Handled all aspects of running the business including, but not limited to, organizing shifts, facilitating meetings, addressing conflicts, running workshops and handling deposits.

Amherst, MA

EDUCATION

March 2015 - May 2015

General Assembly – UXDi

UX Design Immersive Program San Francisco, CA

Sept. 2010 - May 2014

Computer Science – BS

Umass Amherst Amherst, MA

PROJECTS -

April 2015

ProtoHack – GivJoy

Givjoy is a mobile appliction for allowing a person to bring joy to their friends. GivJoy was created at ProtoHack, a codefree hackathon, in 7 hours. San Francisco, CA

January 2014

Meet & Eat - M&E

Meet & Eat is an app designed to allow users to organize meetups with friends to get a bite to eat.

Amherst, MA

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3 LESS, SASS JavaScript, jQuery Sketch, Adobe CC, Framer, Invision, Git, Node.js Bootstrap

BackboneJS